Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series V: Audio-Visual Material, 1985-2012
  - Subseries D: Audiocassette Tapes, 1985-2002
    - FireGround: Communications, Tracking and Information Management A Forum Series on Technology for Public Safety and Security, Thursday April 18, 2002. U.S.I., Tape 4 (2), 2002 April 18 (Box 48, Cassette 23)
    - Assumptions about the Progress of Knowledge, Tape #2, 3064-90, Undated (Box 48, Cassette 24)
    - Continuation of Progress of Knowledge, Tape #3, 3064-90, Undated (Box 48, Cassette 25)
    - Bridging the Two Cultures through STS Education, Barlow, Matthews & Bugliarello, The 6th Annual Technological Literacy Conference, February 1-3, 1991, Washington DC, 1991 February 1-3 (Box 48, Cassette 26)
    - Classes, Fall 2004, 2004 September 8 (Box 49, Cassette 1)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 September 10 (Box 49, Cassette 2)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 September 22 (Box 49, Cassette 3)
    - Sustainable Cities Class, 2004 September 24 (Box 49, Cassette 4)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 September 29 (Box 49, Cassette 5)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 October 1 (Box 49, Cassette 6)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 October 8 (Box 49, Cassette 7)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 October 15 (Box 49, Cassette 8)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 October 20 (Box 49, Cassette 9)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 October 29 (Box 49, Cassette 10)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 November 10 (Box 49, Cassette 11)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 November 12 (Box 49, Cassette 12)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 November 19 (Box 49, Cassette 13)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 November 24 (Box 49, Cassette 14)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 December 1 (Box 49, Cassette 15)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 December 3 (Box 49, Cassette 16)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 December 8 (Box 49, Cassette 17)
    - Sustainable Cities, 2004 December 10 (Box 49, Cassette 18)
    - Sustainable Cities – Bill Shore, 2004 October 6 (Box 49, Cassette 19)
    - Sustainable Cities – Bill Shore, 2004 October 22 (Box 49, Cassette 20)
    - Sustainable Cities – Bill Shore, 2004 November 3 (Box 49, Cassette 21)
    - Sustainable Cities – Bill Shore, 2004 November 5 (Box 49, Cassette 22)
    - Sustainable Cities – Bill Shore, 2004 November 17 (Box 49, Cassette 23)
    - Unnamed, Undated (Box 49, Cassette 24)
    - Turkey, STS, Undated (Box 49, Cassette 25)
    - The Seattle Forum, 1998 (Box 49, Cassette 26)
    - Illegible, 2004 October 13 (Box 49, Cassette 27)
    - Joseph Jacobs – Leadership Seminar Lecture, 1994 October 17 (Box 49, Cassette 28)
    - Standard Cassette Transcriber - Panasonic, Undated (Object 1)
- Series VI: Speeches & Presentations
  This series contains transcripts and notes from speeches, presentations and lectures given by George Bugliarello at national and international conferences, symposiums and other events.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - "Technological Literacy and Beyond: Education and the Social Integration of Technology" – American Association Engineering Societies, 1983 Public Affairs Forum, 1983 October 6 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - "The Technological University and the Construction of the Future" – 25th Anniversary Symposium, Oakland University, 1984 November 12 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - "Technology and the City" – New York Science Policy Association – New York Academy of Science, 1987 October 6 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - "The Assessment of Technology Assessment: A View to the Year 2000" – International Association for Impact Assessment – New York, NY, 1984 May 24 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - "Science, Technology, & Religion" – Religion in America – Princeton Club, New York, New York, 1985 December 3 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - "Commercial Space Vehicles: Opportunity Out of Adversity" – New York Times Op-Ed – Drafts, 1986 September (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - "University / Industry Interaction" – North Coast Business Conference – Erie, PA, 1986 October 1 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - "University as an Instrument of Technological Innovation" – Innovare – Naples, Italy, 1986 November 28 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - "The Paint and Coatings Industry: A Speculation About the Future" – New York Paint and Coating Association, 1987 February 26 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - "Technology and the City – The Crucial Turning Point" – Conference on Crisis and Planning: The Transformation of the City and of Work – Genoa, Italy, 1984 November 21 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - "The Road to Mini-America" – The Proposed Administrative Budget for Education, [1987] (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - "The Technology Agenda" – Drafts, [1987] (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - George Bugliarello Statement Before the Subcommittee on Science Research and Technology Committee on Science and Technology – U.S. House of Representatives, 1988 February 17 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - "The Challenge to the Engineering Schools" – International Forum on Engineering Education – Washington, DC, 1988 December 1 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Technology Literacy Guidelines – Teachers Clearinghouse, 1990 Spring (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - "Challenges of the Changing Economy of N.Y.C." –Proceedings of the 23rd Annual One-Day Institute Sponsored by N.Y.C. Council on Economic Education at Baruch College, 1990 May 9 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - "The Challenges of Providing Future Infrastructure in an Environment of Limited Resources…" – Board on Infrastructure and the Constructed Environment – N.R.C., 1995 March 24 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - "Financing Tomorrow's Infrastructure: Challenges & Issues – Board on Infrastructure and the Constructed Environment – N.R.C., 1995 October 20 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - "The Automobile in America" – Presentation to the General Motors Italy – OPEL Italia Delegation, 1996 January 6 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Workshop on Integrated Infrastructure Research - New York University, 1996 July 15-17 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - "The Future of Science and Engineering" – Keynote Speech – Sci-Tech II Symposium – Adelphi University, 1996 November 2 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - "Technology, Innovation & Global Business" – The First Annual Seattle Forum, 1998 May 28-29 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Keynote Address Presentation – NSF Workshop – Engineering the Service Sector – Georgia Institute of Technology – Atlanta, GA, 2001 July 23-24 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - "Science, Technology and Society: The Tightening Circle" - Materials, Science & Technology 2006 Lectures, 2006 May-June (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - "Some Thoughts on Engineering and Sustainable Development: Fostering Technology, Innovation and Production" - World Congress & Exhibition: Engineering 2010 – Argentina, 2010 June 11 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Cooper Union Talk, 2010 December (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - "Engineering and the Crossroads of our Species", Undated (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Report on the President's Commission on Inefficiencies in the Design of Humans, Undated (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - "Some Thoughts on Technology of the Environment and the NAE Challenge", Undated (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - "Telecommunications, Telecommunities and National Sovereignty: A New Game", Undated (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - Power Point presentations - 1, 2009-2010 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Power Point presentations - 2, 2008-2010 (Box 50, Folder 32)
  - Power Point presentations - 3, 2009-2010 (Box 50, Folder 33)
  - Power Point presentations - 4, 2006-2010 (Box 50, Folder 34)
  - Power Point presentations - #1-15, Undated (Box 50, Folder 35)
  - Power Point presentations - #16-28, Undated (Box 50, Folder 36)
  - Power Point presentations - #29-42, Undated (Box 50, Folder 37)
  - Power Point presentations - #43-52, Undated (Box 50, Folder 38)
  - Power Point presentations - Copies - AAAS - Urban Sustainability, Undated (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1967-1986 (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Speeches - Miscellaneous, 1987-1997, Undated (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - Speeches - Event Programs - Miscellaneous, 1979-1990 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Speeches - Event Programs - Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Speeches - Event Programs - Miscellaneous, 1993, 1997, Undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Speaking Events, 1973-1984 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Speaking Events, 1985-1990 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Speaking Events, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Correspondence
  This series contains mostly miscellaneous correspondence. Correspondence with a significant number of documents have been separated and given their own folders.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent.
  - Steve Arnold, 2004 November (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Richard Bellingham - Sustainable Glasgow Initiative, 2010 August-September (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Richard Bellingham, 2010-2011 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Ricky Calcao – Admissions – RESTRICT, 2011 January (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Luca Caracoglia, 2001 November-December (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Jack Chesler – RESTRICT, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Lawrence Chiarelli – "Dream Team Recruits", 2010 August (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Porter Cogeshall – Naval Forces Review, 2010 September (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Jack Day - University of Wisconsin – Green Bay, 2010 December - 2011 February (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Earth Systems Engineering, 2002 August (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Dr. Andrey E. Egorov – St. Petersburg State Architectural and Civil Engineering University, 2005 April-November (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Fred Eirich, 2003 July (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Masoud Ghandehari, 2010 October-November (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Daniel Goodman – RESTRICT, 2005 August-September (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Richard E. Hanley – RESTRICT, 2005, 2007 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Hofstra University, 2010 February (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Barbara Kates-Garnick, 2009 September - 2010 May (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Barbara Kates-Garnick, 2009 June-September (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Dr. Melissa Knothe Tate – RESTRICT, 2010-2011 (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - William A. Kuperman, 2005 January (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - Dato Lee Yee-Cheong – World Federation of Engineering Organizations, 2003 June - 2004 November (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Gene Luntey, 2001 June 9 (Box 51, Folder 28)
  - Tony Marjoram – UNESCO, 2004 March-May (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Dr. Hans Mark, 1998-2004 (Box 51, Folder 30)
  - Peter A. Mckenzie – Cobos, Ellington, Maduabum & Mckenzie LLC, 2010 April (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Megacities Project - Janice Perlman, 2001 June - 2002 December (Box 51, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1983 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1997 (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1992 (Box 51, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993, 1993 June-November (Box 51, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1994, 1994 June-July (Box 51, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997, 1997 July-December (Box 51, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous, 2009-2010, 2009 December, 2010 September (Box 51, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous, 2010, 2010 April (Box 51, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 51, Folder 41)
  - Bala Mulloth – Reference Letter – RESTRICT, 2011 January (Box 51, Folder 42)
  - Dr. Norman P. Neureiter, 2010 December 17 (Box 51, Folder 43)
  - Dr. Norman P. Neureiter – Indo-US Science & Technology Forum, 2010 May-June (Box 51, Folder 44)
  - Diya Obeid, 2003 May (Box 51, Folder 45)
  - Janka Ovcharovichova – Harrisburg Area Community College, 2010 September (Box 51, Folder 46)
  - Dr. Baldev Raj – Sustainable Cities, 2010 July-September (Box 51, Folder 47)
  - Elizabeth Dianne Rekov – "The New Frontiers in Engineering Design" Symposium, 2008-2010 (Box 51, Folder 48)
  - Andrew W. Reynolds – Deputy Science and Technology Adviser to the Secretary of State, 2004 March-April (Box 51, Folder 49)
  - Adolph Rodriguez, 2002 March 8 (Box 51, Folder 50)
  - Subrata Saha – 6th International Conference on Ethical Issues in Biomedical Engineering, 2010 May - 2011 March (Box 51, Folder 51)
  - Subrata Saha – Ethics in Biology, Engineering & Medicine an International Journal, 2009-2010 (Box 51, Folder 52)
  - Subrata Saha – Ethics in Biology, Engineering & Medicine an International Journal, 2011 (Box 51, Folder 53)
  - George Schillinger, 2008 December - 2009 December (Box 51, Folder 54)
  - Pasquale M. Sforza, 2005 February (Box 51, Folder 55)
  - Harold P. Sjursen – History and Philosophy of Science and Technology Program, 2007 August (Box 51, Folder 56)
  - George Smith, 1999 November (Box 51, Folder 57)
  - Dr. Subra Suresh, 2010 October (Box 51, Folder 58)
  - University of Manitoba – Dr. Richard Gordon, 2010 August, October (Box 51, Folder 59)
  - Richard Wener, 2005 February (Box 51, Folder 60)
  - Debora Wince-Smith, 2005 January (Box 51, Folder 61)
  - Walter B. Wriston, 1995 September 18 (Box 51, Folder 62)
  - Siro Polo Padolecchia (last descendent of Marco Polo) - Correspondence (Oversize), 2007-2008 (Box 58, Folder 1)
- Series VIII: Photographs & Slides
  This series contains photographs ranging from 4"x6" to 8"x10" which include formal portraits, images of George Bugliarello attending University events, a series of photographs of MetroTech construction and a series of photographs of a Russian delegation visit to the Polytechnic campus. The slides depict MetroTech construction, text, and figures used by George Bugliarello for presentations.
  - Subseries A: MetroTech Construction, 3"x 5" color prints
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Jay Street, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Groundbreaking, 1990 April 19 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Moving Historic Houses – Construction, 1990 March (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous– Construction, Undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - MetroTech Commons, Undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Renaissance Plaza, 1983-1998 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Union Gas, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Chase, 1991 October (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - S.I.A.C. – Construction, 1988 March (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Construction, 1988-1993 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Metrotech and Related Photos, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: U.S.I., 3"x 5" color prints
    - Russian Delegation Visit – Academy of Sciences Anti-terrorism Task Force – 1, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Russian Delegation Visit – Academy of Sciences Anti-terrorism Task Force – 2, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Russian Delegation Visit – Academy of Sciences Anti-terrorism Task Force – 3, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Subseries C: George Bugliarello, 3" x 5" to 8" x 10" black and white and color prints.
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Headshots, 2001 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Posed, Undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Posed, 1989 January (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - MetroTech, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Negatives, 1982, Undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Headshots, circa 1973-2011 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Events - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Mayor Ed Koch, Mayor's Commission for Science and Technology, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Mayor Ed Koch, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - U.N. Ambassadors, Undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Seminar - I.C.E., Undated (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Meeting in Bern Dibner Library, 1993 August (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Luncheon, 1993 October 18 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Event – Miscellaneous, 1990 February 21 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Female Speaker (Unknown), Undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Gruman Hall, circa 1976 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Commencements, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Subseries D: University Relations, circa 1973-2011
    Provenance
    The following folders were transferred from the University Development Office photo collection (H11-074).
    - Photo File - 1, circa 1973-2011 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Photo File - 2, circa 1973-2011 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Photo File - 3, circa 1973-2011 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Photo File - 4, circa 1973-2011 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Subseries E: Slides, Undated; 35mm slides in 2" x 2" mounts. (Box 54)
    Scope and Content
    This box contains miscellaneous containers of labeled and un-labeled slides of images of MetroTech construction and various presentations given by George Bugliarello on university and urban development.
  - Subseries F: Miscellaneous
    - Polytechnic University Long Island Center, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Poster/Comic Strip (Learning Aid?), undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Oversized slides, Poly statistics, undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Series IX: Ephemera
  This series contains a collection of business cards and name tags collected by George Bugliarello. The name tag collection, which was transferred from George Bugliarello's home, represents nearly forty years of George Bugliarello's academic and professional activities.
  - Business Cards (Box 57, Box 55)
  - Nametags (Box 56)
  - George Bugliarello Memorial Day in Brooklyn certificate. Office of the President, Borough of Brooklyn, City of New York., April 27, 2011 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Metrotech Hard Hat, December 12, 1990 (Box 57)
  - Mayor's Award for Excellence in Science and Technology, March 6, 2001 (Box 57)
- Series X: Hard drive, 1998-2011; (2.56 GB, 6,663 files, 222 folders)
  The contents of George Bugliarello's hard drive from the Chancellor's Office, Jacobs Building (Room 350) were transferred to the archives in January 2011 and are retained on a dedicated archives server. The hard drive contains 2.56GB of data in 6,663 files. These digital files have not been reorganized or altered from their original state.
- Series XI: 2022 Accretion, 1996-2014
  Scope and Contents
  These items are a 2022 accretion to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello and consist of publications written or edited by Bugliarello. These items had been pulled from the collection and set aside as possible duplicates. Upon closer inspection, unique items were identified, resulting in this accretion. The accretion is located on bay 33, shelf 6E.
  - East-West Technology Transfer: New Perspectives and Human Resources edited by George Bugliarello, et al., 1996 (Box 59, Item 1)
  - Intellectual Property and Global Markets: An East-West Dialogue edited by George Bugliarello, et al., 1999 (Box 59, Item 2)
  - A Report for the National Institute of Standards and Technology reviewed by George Bugliarello, et al., 2002 (Box 59, Item 3)
  - Knowledge Economics: Emerging Principles, Practices and Policies by George Bugliarello, 2005 (Box 59, Item 4)
  - Livable Cities of the Future: Proceedings of a Symposium Honoring the Legacy of George Bugliarello, 2014 (Box 59, Item 5)
  - The Biosoma: Reflections on the Synthesis of Biology, Society and Machines by George Bugliarello, 2003 (Box 59, Item 6)